Boma: Hello?
Chase Wright: Hello.
Boma: Yeah, I don't know if you saw my… got my message. My network is a little bit flaky.
Boma: And I might be dropping on…
Boma: Can you hear me?
Chase Wright: Yep, are you?
Boma: Okay, can you… I was asking if you got my message.
Chase Wright: Yeah, yeah, I got your message.
Chase Wright: Are you…
Boma: Okay.
Chase Wright: is… I don't… I'm just…
Boma: My network is flaky, so I might not be able to, like.
Boma: Anchor the call, in a way, so…
Chase Wright: I'm just waiting for more people to show up.
Boma: Okay, okay, thank you.
Chase Wright: Alright, I don't know if anyone else is gonna come, so I'll just start on the first agenda item.
Chase Wright: First agenda item is this pull request 867. I don't think anyone has any Objections to this?
Chase Wright: There's a new… there's a new test to require
Chase Wright: Debug, get raw receipts to accept a block cache.
Chase Wright: Seems fine.
Chase Wright: And yes, Barnabas, it is generally this quiet.
Chase Wright: Very few people show up to this call, unfortunately.
Chase Wright: So…
Barnabas: They're gonna be created quite easily, right?
Chase Wright: What's that.
Barnabas: And that means that the standards can be created quite easily.
Chase Wright: Yeah, totally, man, totally.
Chase Wright: Anyway,
Chase Wright: Yeah, so, I don't think anyone has any objections to this. I, all of the clients that we tested passed except, ethrex, and they already agreed that they were going to,
Chase Wright: Look at it and fix it, so…
Chase Wright: I already approved it, unless anyone has any objections, I think I can probably just merge it after this call.
Chase Wright: Let's see, then the second one…
Chase Wright: On the agenda is gonna be this guy, pull request 863.
Chase Wright: It's just, it's just a clarification, adding an example into the spec.
Chase Wright: I asked the author to fix… to fix the example, they fixed it, I've approved it.
Chase Wright: This has no impact on anything other than showing the example in the docs.
Chase Wright: So, again, I already approved it, unless someone
Chase Wright: Objects, I can merge it after this call.
Chase Wright: Let's see what's next.
Chase Wright: Yeah, okay, so the next one… this is one that we did not discuss in the,
Chase Wright: ACDT stand up, but this is…
Chase Wright: basically the same problem as the ACDT stand-up. We need HiveChain updated for this one.
Chase Wright: So… This one, as far as I could tell, is… is fine.
Chase Wright: I don't think there's anything really blocking it.
Chase Wright: Other than there is a PR.
Chase Wright: for ETHREX, That I created. So someone from the ethrex team probably needs to…
Chase Wright: to look at that. We can tag them in Discord and see if we can get someone to look at that.
Chase Wright: Let's see…
Chase Wright: This… the next PR, which is, 8.59, it had comments from LightClient.
Chase Wright: He, he asked a question and then did not follow up, so I'm gonna…
Chase Wright: I'm gonna ask him if he can…
Chase Wright: Comment…
Chase Wright: So, yeah, I just… I just tagged him in the…
Chase Wright: in the issue, because I don't… I don't know what to do with his comment.
Chase Wright: Unfortunately.
Chase Wright: Let's see… So… The next one…
Chase Wright: is 8.52. We discussed this in the AllCoreDevs testing already.
Chase Wright: So I probably just won't go over it in detail again. Same basic premise, we need… we need HiveChain to be updated.
Chase Wright: Then… The next one is a Hive PR that, once again.
Chase Wright: I need light clients to either approve or… Or elaborate on?
Chase Wright: And then the next one is updating HypeChain, which…
Chase Wright: Again, Like Clients is supposed to be reviewing.
Chase Wright: Let's see, what else?
Chase Wright: Okay, so, Boma, you created the agenda. It looks like 787.
Chase Wright: And… What's the other one? Oh, 801?
Chase Wright: Yeah, so… s… these two… These two PRs are the same thing,
Chase Wright: 787 is… Trying to address the issue but it's only spec?
Chase Wright: So it's only… yeah, it's only the spec.
Chase Wright: And then, my AO1… is… Adding the actual fixtures
Chase Wright: for the spec. So, mine supersedes… 787.
Chase Wright: But unfortunately, no one has… Reviewed or said anything?
Chase Wright: for PR801, so, like, I don't know…
Chase Wright: what the holdup is. I don't know if we should…
Chase Wright: take it to Discord, or, take it to the other clients.
Chase Wright: Or if we should just merge it.
Chase Wright: I don't know if anyone has an opinion.
Boma: We have some clients in here, they can chime in.
Chase Wright: We have one client in here, and Barnabas.
Chase Wright: We've got another one.
Boma: If,
Boma: They can't give us, like, a thumbs up or something, then we can track the other clients to see what they think about it.
Chase Wright: Yeah, maybe I'll just post it in,
Chase Wright: I'll just post it in the Discord, see if we can get some feedback on this.
Chase Wright: I don't know what the best channel to post it in, though.
Chase Wright: Alright, whatever. I'll do it, do it later.
Chase Wright: Let's see…
Chase Wright: What's this comment? Is it a comment? Oh, okay.
Chase Wright: Okay, so that's… yeah, that's Hive. So we talked about that in the,
Chase Wright: They're AllCoreDev testing, Paul, so we don't need to… Go over that again.
Chase Wright: The… the next one… Okay.
Boma: About… about… you're talking about, 1585, right?
Chase Wright: Let me see… what… 105. Yep, that one.
Boma: Yeah, I have, like, some… like, a question, probably. So…
Boma: I want to ask if clients is going to, like, pick up the Prague, blob prompts on their own, because.
Chase Wright: Yes, he said in ACDT, which happened just before this stand-up, that he would review these, and…
Chase Wright: And, and
Chase Wright: Mario Vega also commented that they would look at it and try to get it merged, so…
Chase Wright: So yeah, it's… Someone's… someone's gonna look at it.
Boma: Oh, okay.
Chase Wright: Was that your question?
Boma: No, I had, like, a question on how… because I see that the Prague entry mirrors, Cancun, for example, so, which totally makes sense, but…
Boma: we are not setting any, blob schedule, so I wanted to ask if clients is going to pick up the Prague blob prompts on their own.
Boma: I don't know if my question makes sense.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I… I think so. Yes, they… they have…
Chase Wright: In Hive, they do look at the environment variable and pick up the blob schedule. And then in my…
Chase Wright: In my PR updating to Glamsterdam, we're also setting the BPO schedules, so… It's… Yes.
Chase Wright: They, they should pick it up.
Boma: And also, one last thing about the, 60 million cars.
Chase Wright: Yep.
Boma: will it be okay to have, like, a comment somewhere, like, an inline comment about where it's coming from? Because I believe System EL is default for Get, for example, and also Besu.
Chase Wright: Yeah, yeah, it is…
Boma: Otherwise, it will look like a magic number, because I was actually wondering where it was coming from.
Chase Wright: Oh, yeah, it's coming because GoEthereum defaults to that, and since it's not set, GoEthereum defaults to that. So all of our test fixtures that… that rely on that require that number to be 60 million, because that's the… that's the GetHS default
Chase Wright: So, when the fixtures are generated, they assume it's 60 million gas limit. This affects, like, Nethermind and a couple others who aren't setting 60 million as the default gas limit.
Chase Wright: So, you just wanna… you wanna comment?
Boma: Yeah, to, like.
Boma: point out where it's coming from, because I was literally looking at… trying to figure out, then I had to check Get and Best, so then it's like a default pram or something.
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Chase Wright: Okay, good point. I could probably… I mean, we could probably just…
Chase Wright: Can you leave a comment on the… on that PR? Just leave a comment and ask for it?
Boma: Yeah, yeah, oh yeah.
Chase Wright: 85? Yeah. I mean, that's a good point. It is just a number that appears out of nowhere.
Chase Wright: Alright, and my browser just locked up, that's cool.
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Boma: Barnabas also had a comment, I don't know.
Chase Wright: What was it? Oh, what was it?
Chase Wright: Yeah. Okay.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I'm not… I'm not entirely sure, because Hive runs… Hive imports…
Chase Wright: HiveChain, and then there's no consensus clients, so they just kind of sit there.
Chase Wright: I don't know who… who or what is setting the default gas limit, but…
Chase Wright: I don't think it particularly matters. The only thing that really matters is that all clients agree on what the gas limit is at the time that the RPC request call is made.
Chase Wright: So, that's good.
Chase Wright: call out, but I… Don't think it impacts… Anything currently?
Chase Wright: Okay, so the next one was the…
Chase Wright: this one, which is, A51.
Chase Wright: We talked about this on the ACDT call. No one objects, no one is objecting, it's just a specification
Chase Wright: clarification. I don't think it… I checked, it doesn't break any of the current tests, as far as I could tell, so I agreed that I would merge this after
Chase Wright: this call, unless anyone objected, so I will do that.
Boma: Just a little reminder that we don't have any, test features for bowel.
Chase Wright: Yep.
Boma: I… A toll.
Chase Wright: Yep, I'm aware. So, we brought it up in ACDT, and…
Chase Wright: we… it's… we all know Hive needs to be updated, or Hive Chain needs to get updated. It's on the…
Chase Wright: It's on the… It's on the to-do list.
Chase Wright: This particular PR, though, they just want to get it merged because…
Chase Wright: The spec and all of the clients have already implemented it, so it's just updating the YAML, basically, so…
Chase Wright: I said, okay, so we'll worry about generating tests once HiveChain is updated, but they want to get this merged, and I don't have any objections to it, so…
Chase Wright: I think it's fine.
Chase Wright: Okay, the only thing left is error codes, and there is no update on that front.
Chase Wright: I haven't… I haven't heard from Felix.
Chase Wright: So… I don't know if you want to talk about it anymore, Bama, but… There's really not much…
Boma: I don't… it's just a blocker we… we can't really deal with, because
Boma: Currently, Felix is not here, and then Sims also is not here, so… there's… I don't know. But…
Boma: This particular issue has been extended for, like, More than a year now.
Chase Wright: Yep.
Chase Wright: I don't disagree, but I don't…
Boma: Sorry, I just wanted to ask, is, Felix's vacation, like, will he be coming back anytime soon?
Chase Wright: I… I don't know… I don't know. I think so. He's… he messaged me on… on Wednesday, but he's still technically out of office, so…
Boma: Okay.
Boma: what about our release? Do we… should we plan out a release plan, or…
Chase Wright: I mean, I… I would like to, but then at the same time, like, we have so many…
Boma: issues.
Chase Wright: time issues that I just… like, it…
Chase Wright: like, cutting another beta version with the current issues we have, I mean, it doesn't serve any Purpose.
Boma: Okay, what if we kind of, like, make it, like, our priority list that we need these high issues to get met so that we can cut a release and then have, glance to them? I think they've made it?
Boma: So, magic.
Chase Wright: I mean, I think we could… we could probably create, like, a… a meta-issue.
Chase Wright: And just track what… what we want to get done before we cut the next one?
Chase Wright: We could probably do that.
Chase Wright: Alright, so we'll… We'll do that.
Chase Wright: I'll add it… I'll add it to my to-do list.
Boma: Then, we would also need to, like, bump, like, clients.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I know.
Chase Wright: Alright, does anyone have anything else? Anything else to talk about?
Barnabas: Can you not just get maintainer access, Chase?
Chase Wright: Can I what?
Barnabas: Can you not just get maintainer access to this room?
Chase Wright: I have maintainer access to execution APIs. I do not have it to Hive.
Barnabas: Yeah, too high, I meant.
Chase Wright: I mean, there's… there's a big difference between, like, me getting maintainer access and having actual engineers review PRs and appro… and, like, do stuff, like…
Barnabas: I mean, like.
Chase Wright: If I write the PR, someone else should review it, not just.
Barnabas: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Barnabas: I'm not saying that it doesn't need to be reviewed, I'm saying that stuff could still be deployed, stuff could still be running, and we could check against it.
Barnabas: Even if it's not sitting in main, or master.
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Barnabas: So, like, we need to have… we need to have those branches out for DevNets, at least, so that we can make progress.
Barnabas: And then once, you know, people are back from holidays or whatever, they can take a review, and they will be able to actually see, okay, this is a deployed version, it actually is working, and it's a lot easier to review the code that way.
Barnabas: So just get maintainer access, create your branches, whatever you need.
Barnabas: And we'll just get it done.
Chase Wright: Okay. I mean, yeah, I can… I could try. I… my only hesitation with that is, like.
Chase Wright: The… the… the branch diff necessary to make this happen is…
Chase Wright: is very large, and so if I can't get someone to review the smaller PRs, I don't know who's gonna review the…
Chase Wright: like, massive branch stiff, but I can… I can try.
Barnabas: I mean, isn't the branch diff just… should be, like, a one-liner? Like, hey, here's the branch that you should be using?
Chase Wright: I don't… I don't understand what you mean by that. Like, I have to create a branch in Hive to generate.
Barnabas: Yeah.
Chase Wright: They're damn… Hive chain, and that is already, like.
Chase Wright: I mean, that… that alone is already, like… I don't know how many… lines, and then… like… I mean…
Chase Wright: I don't know. There's, like, multiple… and it's not just updating it for that, like, there's other stuff in it also, like,
Chase Wright: there's, like, spec check stuff, so, like, testing against the open JSON RPC, like, there's other stuff in it, so it's… it's big. If I can get, like, client to review it all, that would be nice.
Chase Wright: But yes, I understand your point. If I get maintainer access to Hive, I can create a branch and just point everything at the branches. I mean, I could… I could try.
Barnabas: Yeah, that's okay.
Barnabas: Let's not get blocked on…
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Barnabas: Nothing.
Boma: What, what, so, so…
Boma: Just like, client teams are doing, like, having, them at 6, 7 branches, similar to that, right?
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Boma: Okay.
Chase Wright: So, so basically, we would create a branch off execution APIs called, you know.
Chase Wright: Glamsterdam, or whatever, and then out in Hive, create another branch called Glamsterdam, and then those two branches… then execution APIs can point at that, and Hive can point at GoEthereum DevNet branch 8, or whatever, right? So… so you get the full circular dependency.
Chase Wright: But they're just not being merged into… into main until everything's aligned.
Barnabas: once it hits mainnet or something, you know? Like, that's also fine.
Chase Wright: Was that Boma?
Boma: That could actually, like, help us to cut a release faster, so that when we want to, like, move to main, we can, like, cut a release.
Boma: I don't know if that makes sense.
Chase Wright: Yeah, yeah.
Chase Wright: Makes sense.
Chase Wright: Okay.
Chase Wright: Alright, I guess that's it for this week.
Boma: Alright, thanks.
Barnabas: Thank you. Bye.
Chase Wright: Bye-bye.